<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-17T18:13:03-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CEKlopfenstein</title><subtitle>A place to show and post about personal projects and show examples of my work.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Simple Feeds Gotify Plugin First Release</title><link href="/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2025/08/17/Simple-Feeds.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simple Feeds Gotify Plugin First Release" /><published>2025-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2025/08/17/Simple-Feeds</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2025/08/17/Simple-Feeds.html">&lt;p&gt;Simple Feeds is a simple Gotify plugin that I wrote, mostly because I could, while also serving a practical purpose for me. I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://feeder.co/&quot;&gt;feeder.co&lt;/a&gt; and its associated Chrome plugin since 2022. Initially, to keep track of class announcements, I made use of the fact that the online classroom tool my university used supported RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after graduating, I continued to use it for other news. Mostly related to game sales on Steam. Then sometime in early 2024, I rediscovered that GitHub supports Atom Feeds, which allow you to watch for releases and tags on a GitHub Project. And now having a bit of a Homelab, I had a need to keep informed about those updates. Specifically, so I could keep a lookout for security updates for the software I was hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what better way to embrace Homelabbing than to host my own feed watcher? And given I was already using Gotify for Proxmox Notifications and its plugin support, it seemed like the perfect answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I did search for an existing plugin initially. It turned out that while there was an existing plugin for Gotify to do something, this. Unfortunately, it was more of an external service that would simply send notifications to Gotify using its API, like how Proxmox integrates with it. Which was not exactly what I was looking for. So I decided to build this plugin. Which doesn’t require any external software and has a relatively simple configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;example-screenshots&quot;&gt;Example Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following screenshots are currently deployed and are used to post items from that feed into a Discord server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: When a feed is first added, all items currently visible on the feed will be shown at once. This is not seen here because the notifications were deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    @media (min-width: 500px){
        #gallery0{
            flex-flow: row wrap;
            display: flex;
            justify-content: space-evenly;
            align-items: center;
        }
        #gallery0 &gt; div{
            width: calc(100% - 2.5px);
        }
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;gallery0&quot;&gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/image-box.css&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image0&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
Gotify Main Screen with feed example&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/gotify-plugin/simple_feeds-gotify_main_screen_example.png&quot; alt=&quot;
Gotify Main Screen with feed example&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Gotify Main Screen with feed example&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

    
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image1&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
Gotify Plugins Screen&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/gotify-plugin/simple_feeds-gotify_plugins_screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;
Gotify Plugins Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Gotify Plugins Screen&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

    
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image2&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
Gotify Plugin Screen for Simple Feeds&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/gotify-plugin/simple_feeds-gotify_plugin_screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;
Gotify Plugin Screen for Simple Feeds&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Gotify Plugin Screen for Simple Feeds&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

    
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image3&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
Configuration Screen for Simple Feeds
&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/gotify-plugin/simple_feeds-plugin_config_screen.png
&quot; alt=&quot;
Configuration Screen for Simple Feeds
&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Configuration Screen for Simple Feeds
&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;github-readme&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CEKlopfenstein/simple-feeds&quot;&gt;Github README&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple Gotify Plugin that periodically queries different feeds and publishes new feed items to the attached Gotify Server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graphical User Interface
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Allows the management of feeds (Add/Delete)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support for multiple feed types
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Support of multiple feed types is achieved through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mmcdole/gofeed&quot;&gt;gofeed&lt;/a&gt; library.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Able to determine whether feed items are “new” through different means.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the feed in question does not provide a timestamp for when posts are made, this plugin will fall back on attempting to use the URL of the feed item in question to determine “newness”.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;motivations&quot;&gt;Motivations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I previously was using a Chrome plugin called RSS Feed Reader to watch RSS feeds. But I tend to miss the emails it sends out. I wanted to be able to place the updates of the feeds into a Discord Server. Which can be done using this plugin and my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CEKlopfenstein/gotify-repeater&quot;&gt;Gotify Relay&lt;/a&gt; plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;currently-planned-features&quot;&gt;Currently Planned Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the ability to have separate Gotify “Apps” for separate feeds.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Currently, all feeds go into a single app for the plugin itself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-instructions&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CEKlopfenstein/simple-feeds/tree/master?tab=readme-ov-file#installation&quot;&gt;Installation Instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><category term="golang" /><category term="gotify-plugins" /><summary type="html">Simple Feeds is a simple Gotify plugin that I wrote, mostly because I could, while also serving a practical purpose for me. I’ve been using feeder.co and its associated Chrome plugin since 2022. Initially, to keep track of class announcements, I made use of the fact that the online classroom tool my university used supported RSS feeds.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Assembly Blast From the Past (And First Post of 2025!)</title><link href="/weekly-posts/2025/06/15/Assembly-Blast-From-The-Past.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Assembly Blast From the Past (And First Post of 2025!)" /><published>2025-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/2025/06/15/Assembly-Blast-From-The-Past</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/2025/06/15/Assembly-Blast-From-The-Past.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hey-im-back-again&quot;&gt;Hey I’m back! (Again)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well. What do you know? I’m back online again after only a slight hiatus of, checks notes, 5 months. I guess that’s what happens when life starts happening. But hey no I’m back. Just with less savings and more personal space. Now let’s see what I commited myself too that I happened to miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-years-resolutions-should-be-called-new-years-missed-goals&quot;&gt;New Years Resolutions Should Be Called New Years Missed Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well. I’m a bit late to be setting resolutions this year. So I’ll keep it simply by simply setting the goal of attempting to avoid further needless debt. While also maintaining my current responsibilities at my job. That seems like a good enough goal. But what about last year’s goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;last-years-resolutions&quot;&gt;Last Year’s Resolutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if I’m not putting much effort into resolutions this year. I probably should still look at the goals I had originally set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;--find-a-better-method-of-managing-projects-and-using-it&quot;&gt;- Find a better method of managing projects and using it.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this one. I kind of did it. As seen in my New Year’s post last year I ended up setting up &lt;a href=&quot;https://vikunja.io&quot;&gt;Vikunja&lt;/a&gt;. And while it works I’m still not 100% happy with it. I’ve found that I need something a little less structured which allows for more notes. Just so I can document some random things. I plan on looking into &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TriliumNext/Notes&quot;&gt;TrilliumNext&lt;/a&gt;. But that hasn’t happened quite yet. Mostly because I’ve been rather busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;--make-progress-on-projects&quot;&gt;- Make Progress on Projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great idea in theory. Difficult in practice because I definitely tend to create scope creep on myself. But hey. The only person to disappoint for most of my projects is myself. So no problem there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;--more-regular-monthly-posts&quot;&gt;- More Regular Monthly Posts.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I need to say more on this? Yea failed. I just don’t think I can really keep up with the output required for this, unfortunately. So I don’t plan on enforcing it again any time soon. It was a fun goal though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;--be-more-productive&quot;&gt;- Be More Productive&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have concluded that this was because the projects I was working on at work where reaching a point in which there was very little clear and measurable progress simply due to the nature of the projects. With many of the things that needed done being minor corrections. Which required me to wait for user feedback. But hey recongizing that solved a couple issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-for-the-real-post-assembly&quot;&gt;Now For the Real Post ASSEMBLY!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a bit of a primer on why I ended up doing this little misadventure of a project. A couple of months ago. A friend of mine asked the somewhat rhetorical question “Why are devs so lazy? Why do they feel the need to charge extra to enable encryption?” I ended up answering with a couple of reasons that for many would just be excuses. Such as it technically being more work to support it. That it can cause unexpected slowdowns. And the idea that it’s not always as simply as flipping an enable switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me thinking a bit. Specifically about the performance. So I decided I was going to create a little demo for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-demo&quot;&gt;The Demo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea was simple. Write a program in assembly that takes in an input and “encrypts” or “decrypts” the provided text using a provided key. There being a third option for it to simply spit out what ever it receives as input in as a comparision. I had even done it in my Computer Architecture class as a bit of extra credit. So how hard could it be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So over the course of about 2 weeks in my free time I went about writing said program using the NASM assembler and trusty GDB. Both of which I had to partially relearn how to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, what I ended up with was a program with 5 options. Passthrough, Encode, Decode, Encrypt, and Descrypt. The reason for 5 rather than the originally planned 3 was because of an issue I remembered having when I wrote this for a grade. And that was the “encryption” I’m using isn’t encryption. It’s just simply taking the byte of each character and XORing the bits with some key value. And that can result in unprintable characters. So I ended up setting it up so that the program would encode the resulting “encrypted” message into hexadecimal. Which I tested using the encode and decode options originally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But hey. She works. And while I did originally brainstorm the idea of using RSA encryption rather than simply XORing text. I decided I didn’t want to be working on this project forever. The last time I “implemented” RSA was a couple of years ago in Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And well. This certainly demonstrates some of my comments to my friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a 4.2 megabyte message (which was simply the bible) it took 0.331 seconds to encrypt it and then decrypt it. With the non-encrypted run taking 0.145 seconds. Both tests involved the running of the program twice. The encryption doubles the file size due to the method of encoding. The code needed to encode, decode, encrypt, and decrypt the text taking up nearly half of the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, though this was little more than a thought experiment. Cause I am no wizard in assembly and I’m sure there are more efficient methods to do what I did. But it works as a simple demonstration. Which is all I needed to do. Maybe in the future, I’ll revisit it and actually attempt to implement RSA. But that will be for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in seeing how truely bad my assembly skills are. You are free to look below where I’ll hopefully have a cleaned-up copy of my assembly file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-asm&quot;&gt;; Sys Call numbers.
%define sys_read 0
%define sys_write 1
%define sys_exit 60
%define sys_stdin 0
%define sys_stdout 1
; Max size that can be taken as input to be encrypted.
%define input_max_len 16777216 ; 16 megabytes
; Max size that can be taken in as input to be decrypted.
%define encrypt_max 33554432 ; 32 Megs

; Block Starting Symbol Variables
SECTION .bss
	input: RESB input_max_len
	input_size: RESD 1
	parm_count: RESQ 1
	parm_array: RESQ 1
	encrypt: RESB encrypt_max

; Define variables in the data section
SECTION .data
	start_msg: DB &quot;Assembly Encryption Demo&quot;,0
	linebreak	db	0x0A
	passthrough_parm: DB &quot;--pass&quot;,0
	encrypt_parm: DB &quot;--encrypt&quot;,0
	decrypt_parm: DB &quot;--decrypt&quot;,0
	encode_parm: DB &quot;--encode&quot;,0
	decode_parm: DB &quot;--decode&quot;,0
	help_parm: DB &quot;--help&quot;,0
	parms_required_msg_1: DB &quot;Usage: &quot;,0
	parms_required_msg_2: DB &quot; [--pass] [--encrypt key] [--decrypt key] [--help]&quot;,0x0A,&quot;    --pass: Takes in input and simply spits it back out.&quot;,0x0A,&quot;    --encrypt key: Encrypts the provided text with provided key&quot;,0x0A,&quot;    --decrypt key: Decrypts the provided text with provided key&quot;,0x0A,&quot;    --help: Show this message&quot;,0
	invalid_parm_msg: DB &quot;Invalid Parm: &quot;,0
	end_line: DB 0x0A,0
	output_label: DB &quot;Output:&quot;,0

SECTION .text
	GLOBAL _start

	; Prints out the C style &quot;help&quot; text
	print_usage:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push rax

		mov rax, [rbp+16]
		push rax
		push 0
		push 0
		call get_parm_n
		pop rax

		push start_msg
		call print_line_to_null

		push parms_required_msg_1
		call print_to_null

		push rax
		call print_to_null

		push parms_required_msg_2
		call print_line_to_null

		push 0
		call exit

	; Takes in the starting address of a C style string and prints the contents to
	; the terminal until finding a null. (Queue the issues caused by this security 
	; wise)
	print_to_null:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push rax
		push rdx

		mov rax, [rbp+16]
		push rax
		call strlen
		pop rdx

		push rax
		push rdx
		call print

		pop rdx
		pop rax
		; My method of managing the stack for functions may be questionable.
		; All my functions take in parameters using only values found in the
		; stack. Ignoring all the values found in the registers when entering
		; the function for the most part. The functions also return values 
		; within the stack rather than making use of the registers. Requiring
		; some possibly strange manipulation of the stack. When returning
		; nothing like what happens in this function. The address that ret uses
		; needs moved to where the original first parameter was within the 
		; stack. Then effectively popping off the now unneeded parameters off
		; the stack. This idea is found in all of my functions.
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]  ; The return address into rbp.
		mov [rsp+16], rbp ; Move the return address where the first parameter was originally.
		pop rbp           ; Pop the original value of rbp back into itself.
		add rsp, 8        ; Move the stack pointer so that it's now pointing the new save location of the return address.
		ret               ; Make use of the return address at top of the current stack and return the function.

	; Similar to print_to_null except a new line character is printed out
	; once the string is done being printed.
	print_line_to_null:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push rax
		push rdx

		mov rax, [rbp+16]
		push rax
		call strlen
		pop rdx

		push rax
		push rdx
		call print_line

		pop rdx
		pop rax
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+16], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 8
		ret

	; Generic print method. Takes in an address representing the start of the array 
	; of characters. And a count representing how many characters are within that 
	; array of characters. Using that to print out the characters to the terminal
	; using the sys_out system call.
	print:
		; prep
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		; preserve regs
		push rax
		push rdi
		push rsi
		push rdx
		; do thing
		mov rsi, [rbp+24]
		mov rdx, [rbp+16]
		mov rax, sys_write
		mov rdi, sys_stdout
		syscall ; Preform the Sys Call
		; restore regs
		pop rdx
		pop rsi
		pop rdi
		pop rax
		; return
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]    ; Get a copy of the return address into rbp.
		mov [rsp+24], rbp   ; Copy the return address to the where the first parameter would be.
		pop rbp	            ; pop the original value of rbp back in.
		add rsp, 16         ; Clear the return address in the from it's original address within the stack and clear all values in the stack except for the new copy of the return address.
		ret

	; Same as print except a new line character is printed at the end.
	print_line:
		; prep
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		; preserve regs
		push rsi
		push rdx

		mov rsi, [rbp+24] ; To Print
		mov rdx, [rbp+16] ; Length
		push rsi
		push rdx
		call print

		push linebreak
		push 1
		call print
		; restore regs
		pop rdx
		pop rsi
		; return
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]  ; Get a copy of the return address into rbp.
		mov [rsp+24], rbp ; Copy the return address to the where the first parameter would be.
		pop rbp	          ; pop the original value of rbp back in.
		add rsp, 16       ; Clear the return address in the from it's original address within the stack and clear all values in the stack except for the new copy of the return address.
		ret

	; Read in a string from standard input. Takes in address representing start of 
	; a buffer and another value representing the max value.
	read:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		; preserve regs
		push rax
		push rdi
		push rsi
		push rdx

		mov rsi, [rbp+24]
		mov rdx, [rbp+16]
	
		read_loop:
		mov byte [rsi],0
		inc rsi
		dec rdx
		cmp rdx, 0
		jnz read_loop

	read_loop_end:
		mov rsi, [rbp+24]
		mov rdx, [rbp+16]
		mov rax, sys_read
		mov rdi, sys_stdin
		syscall
		; restore regs
		; return
	read_return:
		pop rdx
		pop rsi
		pop rdi
		pop rax
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]  ; Get a copy of the return address into rbp.
		mov [rsp+24], rbp ; Copy the return address to the where the first parameter would be.
		pop rbp           ; pop the original value of rbp back in.
		add rsp, 16       ; Clear the return address in the from it's original address within the stack and clear all values in the stack except for the new copy of the return address.
		ret

	; Finds the length of a C style string. Only parameter is the address of the 
	; start of the array of characters. The function then counts until it reaches 
	; the null character at the end. Returning the count.
	strlen:
		; prep
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		; Preserve Regs
		push rdx
		push rax
		; Do thing
    	xor   rax, rax
		mov rdx, [rbp+16]
	strlen_loop:
		cmp   byte [rdx], 0
		je    strlen_return
		inc   rdx
		inc   rax
		jmp   strlen_loop
	strlen_return:
		mov [rbp+16], rax
		; Restore Regs
		pop rax
		pop rdx
		; Return
		pop rbp
		ret

	; Get the Nth command line parameter from the provided array.
	; Parameters:
	; 1. Address of parameter array.
	; 2. Count of values in the array
	; 3. Index of N. 
	get_parm_n:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push rcx

		mov rcx, [rbp+16]
		cmp rcx, [rbp+24]
		js get_parm_n_valid
		jz get_parm_n_valid
		mov rcx, 0
		jmp get_parm_n_exit

	get_parm_n_valid:
		imul rcx, 8
		add rcx, [rbp+32]
		mov rcx, [rcx]
		mov [rbp+32], rcx

	get_parm_n_exit:
		pop rcx
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+24], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 16
		ret

	; Exit the program with the provided int value.
	exit:
		; Prep for run
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		; Preserve Regs
		push rax
		push rdi
		; Do thing
		mov rax, sys_exit
		mov rdi, [rbp+16]
		syscall
		; Restore Regs
		pop rdi
		pop rax
		; return
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]  ; Get a copy of the return address into rbp.
		mov [rsp+16], rbp ; Copy the return address to the where the first parameter would be.
		pop rbp	          ; pop the original value of rbp back in.
		add rsp, 8        ; Clear the return address in the from it's original address within the stack and clear all values in the stack except for the new copy of the return address.
		ret

	; Compares two strings. Taking only the addresses of the start of both C-Style 
	; Strings. Returns 0 if they are equal.
	cmp_str:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push rax
		push rdx
		push r8
		push r9

		xor r8, r8
		xor r9, r9

		mov rax, [rbp+24]
		mov rdx, [rbp+16]
	cmp_str_loop:
		cmp byte [rax], 0
		jne cmp_str_str_one_not_ended
		cmp byte [rdx], 0
		je cmp_str_return
		mov r8, 1
		jmp cmp_str_loop
	cmp_str_str_one_not_ended:
		cmp byte [rdx], 0
		jne cmp_str_str_two_not_ended
		mov r8, 1
		jmp cmp_str_return
	cmp_str_str_two_not_ended:
		mov r8b, byte [rax]
		mov r9b, byte [rdx]
		xor r8b, byte [rdx]
		cmp r8, 0
		jnz cmp_str_return
		inc rax
		inc rdx
		jmp cmp_str_loop

	cmp_str_return:
		pop r9
		mov [rbp+24], r8
		pop r8
		pop rdx
		pop rax
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+16], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 8
		ret

	; Main function 1. Simply takes the incoming text and spits it to the terminal.
	; Takes in the address of the buffer and then the max size of said buffer.
	pass_through_text:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push r8
		push r9
		push rax

		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		mov r9, [rbp+16]
	pass_through_text_loop:
		push r8
		push r9
		call read
	
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop rax
		twmp2:
		cmp rax, 1
		jle pass_through_text_done
	
		add r8, rax
		sub r9, rax

		cmp r9, 0
		je pass_through_text_done

		jmp pass_through_text_loop
		
	pass_through_text_done:
		push output_label
		call print_line_to_null

		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		push r8
		call print_to_null
		temp3:

		pop rax
		pop r9
		pop r8
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+24], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 16
		ret

	; Encode the incoming text. Parameters are as follows.
	; Input buffer, Input buffer size, Output buffer, Output buffer size.
	; Output bufffer should be 2x the Size of the input Buffer.
	encode_text:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push r8
		push r9
		push rax

		mov r8, [rbp+40]
		mov r9, [rbp+32]
	encode_text_readin_loop:
		push r8
		push r9
		call read
	
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop rax
	
		cmp rax, 1
		jle encode_text_readin_done
	
		add r8, rax
		sub r9, rax

		cmp r9, 0
		je encode_text_readin_done

		jmp encode_text_readin_loop
		
	encode_text_readin_done:
		mov r8, [rbp+40]
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop r9

		push r8
		push r9
		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		push r8
		mov r8, [rbp+16]
		push r8
		call encode_binary

		mov r8, [rbp+16]
		imul r9, 2
		cmp r8, r9
		jge encode_text_done
		mov r9, r8

	encode_text_done:
		push output_label
		call print_line_to_null

		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		push r8
		push r9
		call print_line

		pop rax
		pop r9
		pop r8
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+40], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 32
		ret

	; Decodes the incoming text.
	; Parameters as follows. Input Buffer, Input Buffer Size, Output Buffer, Output 
	; Buffer Size.
	; Ouput buffer should be at least half the size of the input buffer or more.
	decode_text:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push r8
		push r9
		push rax
		push rdx

		mov r8, [rbp+40]
		mov r9, [rbp+32]
	decode_text_readin_loop:
		push r8
		push r9
		call read
	
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop rax
	
		cmp rax, 1
		jle decode_text_readin_done
	
		add r8, rax
		sub r9, rax

		cmp r9, 0
		je decode_text_readin_done

		jmp decode_text_readin_loop
		
	decode_text_readin_done:
		mov r8, [rbp+40]
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop r9
	
		push r8
		mov r8, r9
		and r8, 0b1
		cmp r8, 0
		je decode_even_count
		sub r9, 1

	decode_even_count:
		push r9
		mov r8, [rbp+24]

		push r8
		mov r8, [rbp+16]
		push r8
		call decode_binary

		mov r8, [rbp+16]
		mov rax, r9
		mov rdx, 0
		mov r11, 2
		div r11
		mov r9, rax
		cmp r8, r9
		jge decode_text_done
		mov r9, r8

	decode_text_done:
		push output_label
		call print_line_to_null

		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		push r8
		push r9
		call print

		pop rdx
		pop rax
		pop r9
		pop r8
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+40], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 32
		ret

	; Encrypts the incoming text.
	; Parameters as follows. Key String Address, Key String Length, Input Buffer, 
	; Input Buffer Size, Output Buffer, Output Buffer Size.
	; Output buffer should be at least twice the size of the input buffer.
	encrypt_text:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push r8
		push r9
		push rax
		push r10
		push r11

		mov r8, [rbp+40]
		mov r9, [rbp+32]
	encrypt_text_readin_loop:
		push r8
		push r9
		call read
	
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop rax
	
		cmp rax, 1
		jle encrypt_text_readin_done
	
		add r8, rax
		sub r9, rax

		cmp r9, 0
		je encrypt_text_readin_done

		jmp encrypt_text_readin_loop
		
	encrypt_text_readin_done:
		mov r8, [rbp+40]
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop r9

		push r8
		push r9
		mov r10,[rbp+56]
		mov r11,[rbp+48]
		push r10
		push r11
		call xor_str_with_key

		push r8
		push r9
		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		push r8
		mov r8, [rbp+16]
		push r8
		call encode_binary

		mov r8, [rbp+16]
		imul r9, 2
		cmp r8, r9
		jge encrypt_text_done
		mov r9, r8

	encrypt_text_done:
		push output_label
		call print_line_to_null

		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		push r8
		push r9
		call print_line

		pop r11
		pop r10
		pop rax
		pop r9
		pop r8
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+56], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 48
		ret

	; Decrypt the incoming text.
	; Parameters as follows. Key String Address, Key String Length, Input Buffer, 
	; Input Buffer Size, Output Buffer, Output Buffer Size.
	; Output buffer should be at least half the size of the input buffer or larger.
	decrypt_text:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push r8
		push r9
		push rax
		push rdx
		push r10
		push r11

		mov r8, [rbp+40]
		mov r9, [rbp+32]
	decrypt_text_readin_loop:
		push r8
		push r9
		call read
	
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop rax
	
		cmp rax, 1
		jle decrypt_text_readin_done
	
		add r8, rax
		sub r9, rax

		cmp r9, 0
		je decrypt_text_readin_done

		jmp decrypt_text_readin_loop
		
	decrypt_text_readin_done:
		mov r8, [rbp+40]
		push r8
		call strlen
		pop r9
	
		push r8
		mov r8, r9
		and r8, 0b1
		cmp r8, 0
		je decrypt_even_count
		sub r9, 1

	decrypt_even_count:
		push r9
		mov r8, [rbp+24]

		push r8
		mov r8, [rbp+16]
		push r8
		call decode_binary

		mov r8, [rbp+16]
		mov rax, r9
		mov rdx, 0
		mov r11, 2
		div r11
		mov r9, rax
		cmp r8, r9
		jge decrypt_text_done
		mov r9, r8

	decrypt_text_done:
		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		temp1:
		push r8
		push r9
		mov r10,[rbp+56]
		mov r11,[rbp+48]
		push r10
		push r11
		call xor_str_with_key


		push output_label
		call print_line_to_null

		mov r8, [rbp+24]
		temp2:
		push r8
		push r9
		call print

		pop r11
		pop r10
		pop rdx
		pop rax
		pop r9
		pop r8
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+56], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 48
		ret

	; Apply XOR &quot;encryption&quot; on the input buffer's contents.
	; Parameters as follows. Input Buffer, Input Buffer Length, Key Buffer, 
	; Key Length.
	; Note the results are saved to the input buffer.
	xor_str_with_key:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push rax
		push rdx
		push r9
		push r10
		push r11

		mov rax, 0
		mov rdx, [rbp+40] ; rbp+40 String
		mov r9,  [rbp+32] ; rbp+32 String Length
		mov r10, [rbp+24] ; rbp+24 Key
		mov r11, [rbp+16] ; rbp+16 Key Length

	xor_str_with_key_loop:
		cmp r9, 0
		je xor_str_with_key_return
		cmp r11, 0
		jg xor_str_with_key_xor_char
		mov r11, [rbp+16]
		mov r10, [rbp+24]

	xor_str_with_key_xor_char:
		mov al, [rdx]
		xor al, [r10]

		mov [rdx], al

		inc rdx
		dec r9
		inc r10
		dec r11
		jmp xor_str_with_key_loop
	
	xor_str_with_key_return:
		pop r11
		pop r10
		pop r9
		pop rdx
		pop rax
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+40], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 32
		ret

	; Takes in an input buffer of raw binary and converts it into printable 
	; characters that are basically just the hexadecimal representation of the raw
	; binary.
	; Parameters as follows. Input Buffer, Input buffer length, Output buffer,
	; Output buffer length.
	; Note. Output buffer should be at least twice the size of the input buffer.
	encode_binary:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push rax
		push rdx
		push r9
		push r10
		push r11
		; rbp+16 max encode length
		; rbp+24 encode location
		; rbp+32 Length of byte list
		; rbp+40 Byte list start (to encode)
		mov r11, [rbp+40]
		mov rdx, 0 ; Chars looked at from byte list
		mov r9,	 [rbp+24]
		mov r10, 0 ; chars placed in encode

		encode_binary_loop:
		mov rax, [rbp+32]
		cmp rdx, rax
		jge encode_binary_return
		mov rax, [rbp+16]
		cmp r10, rax
		jge encode_binary_return

		mov rax, 0
		mov al, byte [r11]
		shr al, 4
		and al, 0b1111
		xor al, 0b00110000
		cmp al, 57
		jle	encode_high_nibble_less_than_10
		add al, 7
		encode_high_nibble_less_than_10:
		mov byte [r9], al
		inc r9
		inc r10

		mov al, byte [r11]
		and al, 0b1111
		xor al, 0b00110000
		cmp al, 57
		jle encode_low_nibble_less_than_10
		add al, 7
		encode_low_nibble_less_than_10:
		mov byte [r9], al

		inc r11
		inc r9
		inc r10
		inc rdx
		jmp encode_binary_loop

		encode_binary_return:
		pop r11
		pop r10
		pop r9
		pop rdx
		pop rax
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+40], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 32
		ret

	; Takes in an input buffer that should be a string of hexadecimal values. 
	; And converts it into a binary value that may or may not be printable.
	; Parameters as follows. Input Buffer, Input buffer length, Output buffer,
	; Output buffer length.
	; Note. Output buffer should be at least half the size or larger of the input 
	; buffer.
	decode_binary:
		push rbp
		mov rbp, rsp
		push rax
		push rdx
		push r9
		push r10
		push r11
		; rbp+16 max decode length
		; rbp+24 decode location
		; rbp+32 Length encode
		; rbp+40 Byte list of encode
		mov r11, [rbp+40]
		mov rdx, 0 ; Chars looked at from byte list
		mov r9,	 [rbp+24]
		mov r10, 0 ; chars placed in encode

		decode_binary_loop:
		mov rax, [rbp+32]
		cmp rdx, rax
		jge decode_binary_return
		mov rax, [rbp+16]
		cmp r10, rax
		jge decode_binary_return

		mov al, byte [r11]
		cmp al, 57
		jle	decode_high_nibble_greater_than_9
		sub al, 7
		decode_high_nibble_greater_than_9:
		and al, 0b1111
		shl al, 4
		mov byte [r9], al
		inc r11
		inc rdx

		mov al, byte [r11]
		cmp al, 57
		jle decode_low_nibble_greater_than_9
		sub al, 7
		decode_low_nibble_greater_than_9:
		and al, 0b1111
		or byte [r9], al

		inc r11
		inc r9
		inc r10
		inc rdx
		jmp decode_binary_loop

		decode_binary_return:
		pop r11
		pop r10
		pop r9
		pop rdx
		pop rax
		mov rbp, [rbp+8]
		mov [rsp+40], rbp
		pop rbp
		add rsp, 32
		ret

	_start:
	; Save the parameter addresses into memory
	save_program_parameters:
		mov rax, [rsp]
		mov [parm_count], rax
		add rsp, 8
		mov [parm_array], rsp
		sub rsp, 8

	process_program_parameters:
		mov rax, [parm_count]
		cmp rax, 1
		jz need_help ; If no parms found print message. And exit

		cmp rax, 2
		jz process_single_parm
	
		cmp rax, 3
		jz process_two_parm

		jmp need_help

	process_single_parm:
		mov rax, [parm_array]
		push rax
		push 2
		push 1
		call get_parm_n
		pop rax

		push rax
		push help_parm
		call cmp_str
		pop rdx
		cmp rdx, 0
		je need_help

		push rax
		push passthrough_parm
		call cmp_str
		pop rdx
		cmp rdx, 0
		je passthrough_parm_given

		push rax
		push encode_parm
		call cmp_str
		pop rdx
		cmp rdx, 0
		je encode_parm_given

		push rax
		push decode_parm
		call cmp_str
		pop rdx
		cmp rdx, 0
		je decode_parm_given

		push invalid_parm_msg
		call print_to_null
		push rax
		call print_line_to_null
		jmp need_help

	passthrough_parm_given:
		mov r8, input
		mov r9, input_max_len

		push r8
		push r9
		call pass_through_text
	
		push 0
		call exit

	encode_parm_given:
		mov r8, input
		mov r9, input_max_len
		push r8
		push r9
		mov r8,	encrypt
		mov r9, encrypt_max
		push r8
		push r9
		call encode_text

		push 0
		call exit

	decode_parm_given:
		mov r8,	encrypt
		mov r9, encrypt_max
		push r8
		push r9
		mov r8, input
		mov r9, input_max_len
		push r8
		push r9
		call decode_text

		push 0
		call exit

	process_two_parm:
		mov rax, [parm_array]
		push rax
		push 3
		push 1
		call get_parm_n
		pop rax

		push rax
		push encrypt_parm
		call cmp_str
		pop rdx
		cmp rdx, 0
		je encrypt_parm_given


		push rax
		push decrypt_parm
		call cmp_str
		pop rdx
		cmp rdx, 0
		je decrypt_parm_given

		jmp need_help

	encrypt_parm_given:
		mov rax, [parm_array]
		push rax
		push 3
		push 2
		call get_parm_n
		pop rax
	
		push rax ; First parm of encrypt_text
		push rax ; First parm of strlen which will be replaced with length or second parm of encrypt_text
		call strlen
	
		mov r8, input
		mov r9, input_max_len
		push r8	; Third Parm of encrypt_text
		push r9	; Fourth parm of encrypt_text
		mov r8,	encrypt
		mov r9, encrypt_max
		push r8 ; Fifth
		push r9	; Sixth
		call encrypt_text

		push 0
		call exit

	decrypt_parm_given:
		mov rax, [parm_array]
		push rax
		push 3
		push 2
		call get_parm_n
		pop rax

		push rax ; First parm of encrypt_text
		push rax ; First parm of strlen which will be replaced with length or second parm of encrypt_text
		call strlen

		mov r8,	encrypt
		mov r9, encrypt_max
		push r8
		push r9
		mov r8, input
		mov r9, input_max_len
		push r8
		push r9
		call decrypt_text

		push 0
		call exit

	need_help:
		mov rax, [parm_array]
		push rax
		call print_usage
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><summary type="html">Hey I’m back! (Again)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Initial 3D Printer Escapades</title><link href="/weekly-posts/3d-printing/2024/11/20/3D-Printing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Initial 3D Printer Escapades" /><published>2024-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/3d-printing/2024/11/20/3D-Printing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/3d-printing/2024/11/20/3D-Printing.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s a whole lot later than I had originally planned to post about this. But here we are. My initial escapades with 3D printing since High School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: This post has been in progress since June/July. With periodic work being done. Continuity errors may exist. Especially because the original plan was to post this the 15th of July. (Ouch this is late.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why&quot;&gt;But Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in High School, my school was fortunate enough to have been given funding to purchase and maintain a 3D Printer just before my Freshman Year. It was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seemecnc.com/products/rostock-max-complete-kit&quot;&gt;SeeMeCNC Restock Max V2 3D Printer&lt;/a&gt;, and I was fascinated. So, I took the classes that would eventually allow me to interact with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I got permission from the teacher in charge of the printer (printers by this point) to print something I ended up making in Autodesk Inventor. Which at the time was the software we learned in one of his classes. So I took advantage of it. Until I was accused of burning through a kilogram of filament without saying anything. (It was later discovered that I had not. Another student bought a printer and didn’t have enough money for filament. So he simply stuck it in his backpack and walked out.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it was all said and done, beyond the prints I did for the classes, I ended up with two puzzles. One being a Van Der Poel’s Puzzle, at least that’s what it was called on the solution. And a copy of another wooden puzzle I had previously been exposed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    @media (min-width: 500px){
        #gallery0{
            flex-flow: row wrap;
            display: flex;
            justify-content: space-evenly;
            align-items: center;
        }
        #gallery0 &gt; div{
            width: calc(33% - 2.5px);
        }
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;gallery0&quot;&gt;
    
    
    
    &lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/image-box.css&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image0&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
Assembled Puzzles&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/first-3D-printer/Both%20Puzzles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;
Assembled Puzzles&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Assembled Puzzles&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

    
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image1&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
An example of a simpler puzzle disassembled
&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/first-3D-printer/Pieces.jpg
&quot; alt=&quot;
An example of a simpler puzzle disassembled
&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
An example of a simpler puzzle disassembled
&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image2&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;The 'Solution' to the more complex puzzle. (Pink in the previous image.)&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/first-3D-printer/Van_der_Peols_Puzzle_SOLUTION.png&quot; alt=&quot;The 'Solution' to the more complex puzzle. (Pink in the previous image.)&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 'Solution' to the more complex puzzle. (Pink in the previous image.)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way enough rambling. Since then I’ve wanted to buy myself a 3D printer. But at the time. I was a high school student who didn’t have the funds they could spare. As everything was being saved to pay for college. So that had to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-a-printer&quot;&gt;Choosing a Printer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that was then and this is now. And I have a bit of spending money. But deciding what printer was the next matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I had a few requirements. Many of which are a result of my current living situation. Which is relatively space-constrained. So right off the bat, I needed something small and compact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, my requirements were rather broad. Those being that it’s a decent volume, a cheap price, and wouldn’t be a complete piece of garbage. The logic being that I really don’t want to go all out just yet as I wasn’t entirely sure I would want to continue it as a hobby. I also didn’t want something that would require me to go out and buy 20 things in order for it to give me a simple print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of other things I wanted were features that didn’t exist on the printer I first used. Mostly being Automatic Bed Leveling. Just for the convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;options&quot;&gt;Options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with the requirements decided which one would I get? Well. I looked into quite a few actually with the list below detailing some I considered as well as notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Printer              &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Price                    &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Bed Volume            &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;“Desk” Space    &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Auto Bed Leveling  &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://all3dp.com/1/monoprice-mp-select-mini-3d-printer-review/&quot;&gt;Monoprice Mini Select&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$200&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;120mm x 120mm x 120mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;~430mm x ~360mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;❓ Depends (V2 Maybe?)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/reviews/monoprice-mini-delta-v2&quot;&gt;Monoprice Mini Delta&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$179&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;r55mm x 120mm        &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;~304.8mm x ~304.8mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✔️ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/reviews/bambu-lab-a1-mini&quot;&gt;Bambu Lab A1 Mini&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$249                      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180mm x 180mm x 180mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;347mm x 314mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✔️ Yes (Plus More)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/3d-printing/creality-ender-3-v3-ke-review&quot;&gt;Ender 3 V3 KE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$329&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;220mm x 220mm x 240mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;433mm x 366mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✔️ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/reviews/creality-ender-3-v3-se&quot;&gt;Ender 3 V3 SE&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$249                      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;220mm x 220mm x 250mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;349mm x 364mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✔️ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antonmansson.com/3d-printing-blog/the-final-creality-ender-3-v3&quot;&gt;Ender 3 V3 CoreXZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$349&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;220mm x 220mm x 250mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;349mm x 364mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✔️ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcmag.com/reviews/creality-ender-3-v2&quot;&gt;Ender 3 V2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$209&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;220mm x 220mm x 250mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;475mm x 470mm  &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;❌ No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/reviews/kingroon-kp3s&quot;&gt;Kingroon KP3S 3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$179&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180mm x 180mm x 180mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;390mm x 370mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;❌ No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Table Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desk Size found based on shipping size and presumed packing. Unless found otherwise posted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If available Tom’s Hardware was used to find functionality/sizing. Please consult other sources as well when performing your research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thought-process-on-selection&quot;&gt;Thought Process on Selection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I boil it right down to what was most important for me it was the amount of deskspace it took up. But there’s another thing to consider when you’re looking at that. And that is most of the beds on these printers can move outside of the footprint they may take up. Meaning you not only need the space to have the thing sit. But also the space for it to move. And given my space constraints that only left the Mini Delta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another box it ticked for me was the auto bed leveling. And the fact that, at least according to my research, minimal servicing was needed to make it print decent things. I also was able to find it for $169 shipped before taxes. Making it the cheapest option that met most of my requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the one requirement it only sort of meets is bed size. At a diameter of 110mm by 120mm it isn’t exactly large. And that’s a circle. If I wanted to print the largest square possible the max I can do is a little more than 77mm. But it fits most of my requirements. And while the bed space is small I think it will be workable for some smaller projects. Some more superglue will just have to be involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modeling-software&quot;&gt;Modeling Software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the printer chosen and ordered then began the wait. And the perfect time to start to figure out which software to use. And at this point the option I’ll be going with is FreeCAD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;addendem&quot;&gt;Addendem&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most of the below opinions and thoughts on FreeCAD is now hilariously out of date. Due to most of it being written mostly in June. And with the release of FreeCAD 1.0 may not be valid. Having not installed it yet. I can’t really say for sure though I do know that there is a default assembly workbench which is great.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Either way back to the original post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-what-a-great-price&quot;&gt;Free. What a Great Price!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of reasons for this. And one of which is that it’s free. But that’s not the whole thing. So I originally learned CAD in high school as part of an “engineering” class. In that class, we used Autodesk Inventor. And I explicitly remember, even though it’s been a minute, that I planned to buy it when I could and had a printer. Sure it was expensive, and holy smokes was it, but I was familiar with it. And I thought it would be a one-time purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the same year I had this thought happened to be the first year Autodesk stopped doing perpetual licenses. Meaning that if you wanted it you had to subscribe to it. And I’m not sure if they were the first but all the others seemed to start following suit. And while some of them have hobby levels you can rent for cheaper you are kind of at their whim regardless. So given I was going to have to learn a new piece of software I figured I’d go with the free and Open Source option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And hey. As of writing this, they have even announced a feature freeze in order to prepare for the release of 1.0. Which is even better. I think I might even donate a bit at some point. We’ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning-software&quot;&gt;Learning Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’m no expert. And I’m not going to drone on about how to use FreeCAD. But I will say after learning the different naming conventions I’ve not run into much of an issue. That’s likely because I was never an advanced user of Inventor or any other CAD software but it works so far. I haven’t even run into the dreaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freecad.org/Topological_naming_problem&quot;&gt;Topological naming problem&lt;/a&gt;. However, that’s also something that’s expected to be fixed in 1.0. (Side note. The implementation for the fix to that problem has been activated in the 0.22 weekly builds for the week of June 19th. However, I am not using weekly builds at this point.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn it at a basic level I decided to remodel one of the puzzles I printed in High School figuring they were both simple enough and complex enough for me to learn at least the basic features. And after a couple of hiccups. I did get it to work. I even got it so that I could change some dimensions using a spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image3&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;Screenshot from FreeCAD with Puzzle Pieces and Assembly.&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/first-3D-printer/Basic%20Puzzle%20In%20FreeCAD.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot from FreeCAD with Puzzle Pieces and Assembly.&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Screenshot from FreeCAD with Puzzle Pieces and Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one thing that initially surprised me. And that was the fact that FreeCAD itself does not have a way of creating assemblies by default. I had made use of Inventor Previously in order to make the solved model of the puzzle. In order to do that you need to install a plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there’s actually a couple to choose from. But not wanting to install plugins just yet. I ended up simply using transformations and rotations based on some predefined measurements to create the assembly. Doing this I ended up also making use of the clone feature. Allowing me to still change the original modeled pieces and see the effect on the solved puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-to-get-printing&quot;&gt;Now To Get Printing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I got the printer I ended up doing a single test print before proceeding. A “cat” ring that is on the SD card when you buy it. And it worked without anything screwy going on. So with that, I felt comfortable proceeding to the next step of my plan. Connecting the printer to Octoprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;octoprint-oh-the-power&quot;&gt;Octoprint OH THE POWER!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Octoprint is a very nice piece of software that allows you to control your printer remotely. More importantly, reducing the need to use sneaker net and that SD card in order to print things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it was going to be simple. I’d create a VM on Proxmox, pass through the Printer as a USB device, install Octoprint and I’d be off to the races. Unfortunately, that was not the case. Octoprint kept failing to connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, in my search, I thought it was a common issue with Monoprice Printers and that being that the CH341 driver needed to be updated. Which is apparently a common issue. But after fighting with that due to a couple of different issues it still didn’t work. (&lt;a href=&quot;#ch340ch341ch34x-driver-instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions can be found here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is where it took the longest time. Unfortunately, it appears that the Monoprice Mini V2 specifically does some “nonstandard” (in comparison to most printers) serial handshake. Requiring you to modify Octoprint. And I only found this because WEEDO did this on their “own” printers. The WEEDO x40 also requires this modification. Unfortunately I never found instructions specifically for the Mini Delta V2. But the instructions for the X40 work. My copy of the instructions &lt;a href=&quot;#modify-octoprint-to-function-with-monoprice-mini-delta-v2&quot;&gt;can be found below&lt;/a&gt;. Mostly because I do not fully trust them to not disappear into the wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it took quite a bit of research to find that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-prints-away---or-are-they&quot;&gt;First Prints Away! - Or are they?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Octoprint set up, I began to do some printing as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    @media (min-width: 500px){
        #gallery1{
            flex-flow: row wrap;
            display: flex;
            justify-content: space-evenly;
            align-items: center;
        }
        #gallery1 &gt; div{
            width: calc(33% - 2.5px);
        }
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;gallery1&quot;&gt;
    
    
    
    
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image4&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
Soldier Mini Test Print (In shadow)&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/first-3D-printer/Soldier_Light_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;
Soldier Mini Test Print (In shadow)&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Soldier Mini Test Print (In shadow)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

    
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image5&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
Soldier Mini Test Print (In more direct light)&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/first-3D-printer/Soldier_Light_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;
Soldier Mini Test Print (In more direct light)&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Soldier Mini Test Print (In more direct light)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

    
&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image6&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;
Cube Puzzle
&quot; src=&quot;
/assets/images/first-3D-printer/Fresh_Cube_Puzzle.jpg
&quot; alt=&quot;
Cube Puzzle
&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Cube Puzzle
&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, though it wasn’t as simple as just hitting print. Which was to be expected. What is not pictured is the numerous failed prints and test prints. Some of which one of my cats has taken to stealing off my desk. But lucky enough I am not the first to be working with this printer. And while there seems to be a bigger community around the V1 the V2 has quite a few of the same issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main problem for me is the fact that this community mostly seems to exist within a Facebook group. Which I can’t access because Meta has apparently determined I’m impersonating myself. And to protect myself from myself they deactivate any meta account I attempt to create. Luckily though someone was nice enough to create a complication of many of the more common issues and posted it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/mpminidelta/comments/bzm1s2/updated_mpmd_calibration_guide_and_faq/&quot;&gt;within the subreddit&lt;/a&gt; of all places. Somewhere I can access it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And making use of these I was able to get some generally consistent results. Specifically, I ended up needing to create some clips that the FAQ/Help document recommended. Which fixed layer shifting. The only other major issues I’ve been having has been first-layer issues caused by a rather warped bed. Which I’ve been solving mostly by trial and error. A better solution would likely be to be using rafts. But I really don’t want to deal with removing those later at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-notes&quot;&gt;Final Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I’m happy with it. I’ve even bought another printer at the Midwest RepRap Festival &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/midwestreprapfest/&quot;&gt;(MRRF)&lt;/a&gt;. Which I ended up fixing using the Delta to create a stop-gap measure for a snapped belt and a replacement end cap used to tension the very same belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it appears that I may be using the second printer to fix the Delta now. How fitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said though here I will be including a list of links. Unfortunately, I didn’t keep the best notes for some of these. But I feel like these could be useful for others, or myself for that matter, that may happen onto this post later with the same printer. Either way. Thanks for reading and here they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;random-links&quot;&gt;“Random” Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/mpminidelta/comments/pbe9z4/mini_delta_v2_wont_connect_trough_usb/&quot;&gt;Evidence of it failing to connect over USB (Reddit Post)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/MPSelectMiniOwners/comments/r7uaqz/mp_mini_v2_linux_trouble/&quot;&gt;Evidence that connecting over USB should be possible (Reddit Post)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calibration Roadmap
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RYnJSEOnuf3h62FwhQ2lCmzbucvMLhy7/view&quot;&gt;Google Doc Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/mpminidelta/comments/bzm1s2/updated_mpmd_calibration_guide_and_faq/&quot;&gt;Calibration Roadmap Reddit post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/mpminidelta/comments/wfgajm/mpmdv2_firmware_update/&quot;&gt;Notice of Firmware Update (Reddit Post)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/jaredharley/31e6a05da2a2edf44c5150d839439c9b&quot;&gt;Notes on Web API that the Delta V2 has. (Github Gist)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/piberry/-MPMDv2-modifications-and-fixes&quot;&gt;Mods/fixes (Github)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/puv3chgfzmx7w3apppdco/MonopriceMiniDeltaV2FirmwareFiles.zip?rlkey=3hx029pogg6h6pwfs7h9d6l8j&amp;amp;e=3&amp;amp;dl=0&quot;&gt;Updated Firmware files (Dropbox)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/weedo3d/MiniDeltaV2firmware&quot;&gt;Printer Firmware Github (Note may not work)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;instructionslinks&quot;&gt;Instructions/Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are a series of instructions that may prove useful as well as a couple of links that may provide more information if issues arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ch340ch341ch34x-driver-instructions&quot;&gt;CH340/CH341/CH34X Driver Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;reason-to-use-these-instructions&quot;&gt;Reason To Use These Instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The printer is plugged in. But does not appear under /dev/ttyUSB0 or /dev/ttyACM0. &lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt; also help with general communication issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Following Instructions Derived From these for the Rasberry Pi and the X40 Printer
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weedo3dprinter.com/doku.php/x40/updatech340&quot;&gt;https://www.weedo3dprinter.com/doku.php/x40/updatech340&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Originally linked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/mpminidelta/comments/peotfz/problems_with_mini_delta_v2_and_octoprint/&quot;&gt;in this Reddit post&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; Links leading to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mpminideltav2.com&lt;/code&gt; no longer lead to a wiki. And will lead you no where safe as of writing this. If you want to attempt to use those links attempt to view them through the Way Back Machine. &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20221205011655/http://mpminideltav2.com/doku.php?id=functional_video_display:mp_mini_delta_v2&quot;&gt;Here is a link to the wiki on the Way Back Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.octoprint.org/t/monoprice-mini-delta-v2/36858&quot;&gt;community post&lt;/a&gt; on Octoprint’s site attempts to lead you to a similar tutorial with the same issue as above.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Source Code Used
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Source Code Provided in the Original Instructions did not compile without errors. This seems to compile without those errors.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juliagoda/CH341SER&quot;&gt;https://github.com/juliagoda/CH341SER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MAKE A BACKUP BEFORE PROCEEDING&lt;/strong&gt; These instructions have also only been tested on Ubuntu and Debian. You have been warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete the original Driver
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This should be found at &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/lib/modules/(version)/kernal/drivers/usb/serial/ch341.ko&lt;/code&gt;. For me, it was &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/lib/modules/5.4.0-189-generic/kernal/drivers/usb/serial/ch341.ko&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;build-essentials&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Using the command &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt install build-essential&lt;/code&gt; install the tools needed to compile the driver.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt install git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Linux headers files
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This can be done with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt install linux-headers-$(uname -r)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you prefer to not use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;uname&lt;/code&gt; to get the correct name. You can replace &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$(uname -r)&lt;/code&gt; with the value of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(version)&lt;/code&gt; found in the first step.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clone the GitHub Repository
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git clone https://github.com/juliagoda/CH341SER.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compile the new Driver by navigating into &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CH341SER&lt;/code&gt; and then running &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd CH341SER; make&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move the driver into position and install it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; creates a file called ch34x.ko. It needs to be moved into the same place the old driver was removed from. So it should be something like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/lib/modules/(version)/kernal/drivers/usb/serial/&lt;/code&gt;. For me, it was &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/lib/modules/5.4.0-189-generic/kernal/drivers/usb/serial/&lt;/code&gt;.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This can be done using move or by making a copy.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo cp ch34x.ko /lib/modules/(version)/kernal/drivers/usb/serial/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo depmod&lt;/code&gt; to initialize the drivers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To check that the driver is installed correctly you can plug in the printer using a USB cable and check for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/dev/ttyUSB0&lt;/code&gt;’s existence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modify-octoprint-to-function-with-monoprice-mini-delta-v2&quot;&gt;Modify Octoprint to function with Monoprice Mini Delta V2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;reason-to-use-these-instructions-1&quot;&gt;Reason To Use These Instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WEEDO 3D printers and 3D printers that make use of WEEDO 3D printer boards need this modification in order to allow Octoprint to connect. They do provide their own “version” of Octoprint but I will not advise you to trust it. Especially with how simple the modification is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;links-1&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Original Instructions for WEEDO X40 3D Printer
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weedo3dprinter.com/doku.php/tina2/octoprint&quot;&gt;https://www.weedo3dprinter.com/doku.php/tina2/octoprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;reference-images&quot;&gt;Reference Images&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;before-octoprint-modification&quot;&gt;Before Octoprint Modification&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image7&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/first-3D-printer/Before_Octoprint_Mod.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;after-octoprint-modification&quot;&gt;After Octoprint Modification&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image8&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img title=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/first-3D-printer/After_Octoprint_Mod.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;code-reference&quot;&gt;Code Reference&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#set default
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serial_obj&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setDTR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serial_obj&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setRTS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serial_obj&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Line 3907 of the original source.
# force reboot printer
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sleep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;0.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serial_obj&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setDTR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serial_obj&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setRTS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sleep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serial_obj&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setDTR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serial_obj&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setRTS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# wait
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sleep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;instructions-1&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MAKE A BACKUP BEFORE PROCEEDING&lt;/strong&gt; These instructions have also only been tested on Ubuntu and Debian. You have been warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; These instructions are also assuming you have already installed Octoprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;comm.py&lt;/code&gt; is for your Octoprint install.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For me using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paukstelis/octoprint_deploy&quot;&gt;octoprint_deploy&lt;/a&gt; to install Octoprint &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;comm.py&lt;/code&gt; can be found at &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~/OctoPrint/lib/python3.8/site-packages/octoprint/util/comm.py&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;python3.8&lt;/code&gt; in the path is based on the current version of Python that Octoprint is installed with. It may be different in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modify &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;comm.py&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This modification takes place around &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OctoPrint/OctoPrint/blob/a8fff3930e3c3901bd560ca77656c281959134b3/src/octoprint/util/comm.py#L3907&quot;&gt;line 3907&lt;/a&gt;. As of August 25th this is when Octoprint opens the serial connection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;a href=&quot;#before-octoprint-modification&quot;&gt;before octoprint modification&lt;/a&gt; reference image find the current source code.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make the modifications seen in &lt;a href=&quot;#after-octoprint-modification&quot;&gt;after octoprint modification&lt;/a&gt;. The modified code and the reasons for it are referenced in &lt;a href=&quot;#code-reference&quot;&gt;the code reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reboot your Octoprint instance in order to load the new source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><category term="3D-printing" /><summary type="html">It’s a whole lot later than I had originally planned to post about this. But here we are. My initial escapades with 3D printing since High School.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Razer Naga Trinity Follow-Up</title><link href="/electronics-repair/2024/11/11/mouse-repair-followup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Razer Naga Trinity Follow-Up" /><published>2024-11-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/electronics-repair/2024/11/11/mouse-repair-followup</id><content type="html" xml:base="/electronics-repair/2024/11/11/mouse-repair-followup.html">&lt;p&gt;Well, here I am again. I had originally planned on posting about my 3D printers as my next post. But that has changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you get a short post following up on the repair I posted about &lt;a href=&quot;/electronics-repair/2022/04/17/mouse-repair.html&quot;&gt;April 17th of 2022&lt;/a&gt; where I repaired my Naga Trinity’s left click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-follow-up&quot;&gt;The Follow Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well. After around 2 years the switch once again began failing in the same darn way. Where it would double-click. Likely due to corrosion within the switch from slight arcing. Or at least that’s my best guess. And beyond my best judgment, because I had completely forgotten how difficult it was to remove the switch. I decided I needed to repair it again. With the same iron that was a poor choice last time because the battery on my new one wasn’t charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repair at this point does appear to be a success in terms of restoring functionality once again. The whole job took about 75 minutes this time compared to the 2 hours of soldering I fought through last time. This time it was 10 minutes of me trying to find the screws to realize I had two sets of skids on the mouse. And another hour of struggling to desolder the switch again. Once again destructively removing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But hey. She’s once again fixed. This time with no extra materials needing to be purchased. I just used what I had from last time. But this experience CONCRETELY confirms the fact I need a better iron for this kind of thing. I also need to make sure to put the kittens away next time so they don’t decide that the screws on my work mat are toys. Because I am now down a screw. But I’m “fine” with that since it’s my mouse. Not like I plan on selling it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also appears that since the last time I did this Razer appears to have replaced the Naga Trinity with the Naga Pro V2. So I might get myself one of those if this sucker crokes again. First I’m going to wait for the 2-year mark to hit for its release to see if it suffers the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way. HOPEFULLY the next post is about my printers. That’s the plan atleast.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="electronics-repair" /><summary type="html">Well, here I am again. I had originally planned on posting about my 3D printers as my next post. But that has changed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gotify Repeater Plugin Upgrades (V2 Release)</title><link href="/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2024/06/15/Gotify-Relay-Plugin-Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gotify Repeater Plugin Upgrades (V2 Release)" /><published>2024-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2024/06/15/Gotify-Relay-Plugin-Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2024/06/15/Gotify-Relay-Plugin-Update.html">&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce the release of 2024.2.36 of the plugin. This update was mostly about bug fixes. But does include some new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-improvements&quot;&gt;General Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall most of the changes were to make it easier to develop this plugin further in the future. Such as by automating building and releasing versions on Github when something new is pushed to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch. This also included refactoring some code to reduce some confusion I was having with my organization. Among other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrades-to-release-pipeline&quot;&gt;Upgrades to Release Pipeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the automation of the release pipeline, I ended up automating a couple of other tasks as well. Such as the automatic generation and setting of version numbers within builds. Which is currently achieved using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ldflags&lt;/code&gt; at build time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with that I also gave myself the ability to have two different release types. One that is triggered manually (prereleases) and another that is triggered automatically (full releases). The logic to this being that I want all full releases to be automatically built when I must to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;. Whereas with pre-releases that I might release in the development of a full release, I wouldn’t want to be constantly generated. So they are triggered manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also ended up building a bash script that looks at the current git repository and spits out a version number. Allowing me to “never” think about how I’m numbering things again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;change-logs-can-be-nice&quot;&gt;Change Logs Can Be Nice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the automation of releases, I also ended up setting up a method of writing and maintaining a change log. Currently, there are three files &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MAJOR_CHANGELOG.md&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MINOR_CHANGELOG.md&lt;/code&gt;. With &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/code&gt; being all changes throughout the history of the project. The other two files are then being used in the release process to populate the release message body. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MAJOR_CHANGELOG.md&lt;/code&gt; for the full releases and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MINOR_CHANGELOG.md&lt;/code&gt; for the pre-releases. Simple enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding these files (and their semi-static location) also allowed for me to add a Change Log message within the plugin’s info page within Gotify. With it currently listing only the most recent changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;refactoring&quot;&gt;Refactoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for refactoring. I did not name all my packages in the most sane way when I started. And with my plan to expand the project further. Well, that wouldn’t be wise to leave as is. So before it gets too big I decided to try to come up with some more sane and descriptive package names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll see how well I can maintain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security-through-obscurity&quot;&gt;Security Through Obscurity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for functionality. The only thing that I wouldn’t call a full-fledged feature is the fact that Discord Webhook Links (and in the future other secrets) are now hidden by default unless you hover/click them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is now that I would like to note. Much of the functionality of this plugin is based on my use. And that includes the fact that keys are currently transmitted back to the browser for the transmitters. In the future, I may make it so that isn’t the case. But for now. I do not have an explicit reason to develop said feature due to my current setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these features are simple. And for good reason. The goal was to do this in a month. (Mostly because my projects need a limited timeline otherwise they tend to expand.) So they are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transmitters now record how many times they have been used.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Log messages for the plugin are now accessible in the UI.
    - Log messages in UI are cleared on reboot but are still sent to Standard Out as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Relay Transmitters
    - Discord Advance
        - Makes use of Discord’s Embeds that can be in Webhook messages. 
        - Embeds are not currently fully utilized at this point.
        - The current implementation is more or less the same as the old Discord Transmitter.
    - Pushbullet
        - Very similar formatting to the original Discord Transmitter. Just through Pushbullet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes-every-project-needs-its-exterminator&quot;&gt;Bug Fixes (Every project needs it’s exterminator)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as with many projects. A few bugs are likely to find their way in. And I am not impervious to bugs. So I had a few to fix. Unfortunately, I didn’t discover them until running the plugin myself for a couple of days. They are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed the issues that caused the Transmitters to be spammed with empty messages.
    - Typically happened when the server Gotify was running on had a hiccup elsewhere.
    - Prevention measures put in place to prevent them in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corrected method of reconnecting after a connection is unexpectedly terminated.
    - This could also cause the issue above if it were to happen in a specific case.
    - Currently, if a connection is lost. It will now wait 1 second before trying to reestablish itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-thats-that&quot;&gt;And That’s That&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in all honesty that’s it. Most of this was a rehashing of what you can find in the project’s changes logs &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CEKlopfenstein/gotify-repeater/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. But I’ve set myself a goal of a post a month. So here it is. At least it has some value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a good one. And see y’all next month where I hope to talk about 3D printing. Hopefully, everything pans out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><category term="golang" /><category term="gotify-plugins" /><summary type="html">I am pleased to announce the release of 2024.2.36 of the plugin. This update was mostly about bug fixes. But does include some new features.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Halite 1 - Site Resurrection Attempt</title><link href="/weekly-posts/halite-1/2024/05/15/Halite-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Halite 1 - Site Resurrection Attempt" /><published>2024-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/halite-1/2024/05/15/Halite-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/halite-1/2024/05/15/Halite-1.html">&lt;p&gt;I first got seriously into programming sometime around my freshman year of High School. This is for a few reasons. But one of the reasons I remember doing so was because of a Minecraft Mod called Computercraft. The mod itself added computers as well as robots, called turtles, that players could program in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lua.org/&quot;&gt;Lua&lt;/a&gt;. And I did this quite a bit and it allowed me to get over some self-doubts. As a result of not wanting to test my programs in the limited environment of the game. I later installed a Lua Interpreter. Which allowed for the creation of quite a few other projects I did. And while most are effectively lost at this point. It was a start to my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite a few years later. In my senior year of High School, I ended up finding another “game” that allowed me to discover a fascination with simulations. As well as the idea of programming within a contest. That “game” was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halite_AI_Programming_Competition&quot;&gt;Halite&lt;/a&gt;. And while I never ended up participating in an active contest I enjoyed making bots that could play against each other. Though I can’t say I was ever really good. Either way, it was added to an early version of my Projects list. Though without much description of what to do around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-present&quot;&gt;The Present&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here we are. It’s nearly 5 years later and I’m finally getting around to it. Unfortunately many of the original resources for Halite 1 at this point have mostly been pulled offline beyond the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HaliteChallenge/Halite&quot;&gt;Open Source Repositories on Github&lt;/a&gt;. With the old domains such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;halite.io&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2016.halite.io&lt;/code&gt; are now redirected to the company that created the contest. Who seems to have decided to take all the Halite sites down sometime between September 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; 2022 and October 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; 2022 according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20220101000000*/https://halite.io/&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;. With all requests to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;halite.io&lt;/code&gt; being redirected after October 2022. However, it also indicates that the last successful capture was a 3xx redirect. Aligning with the closing of their last contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-plan&quot;&gt;The Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with the last remaining official resource outside of the Internet Archive being the Github repository. I decided that I would attempt to resurrect the site. At least in a static capacity. I might try to do more in the future. But for now. That’s my set goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;containerize-the-site&quot;&gt;Containerize The Site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first up was to get a “working” containerization of the Website running. Though the instructions within the repository are for a full install of Ubuntu, I’m going this route to reduce my system requirements. As flawed as that idea may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CEKlopfenstein/Halite-1/blob/Website-Docker-Container/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;Contribution Guide&lt;/a&gt; it should be as simple as running some install scripts. But the scripts for whatever reason didn’t work right off the back. So I broke the scripts into RUN commands for building the Docker Image. And this worked for the most part. At least from appearances. The problem though boiled down to the fact that the scripts were meant for a VM. Where installing something like Apache would result in a running service. So I had to figure out how to configure Apache and start it within the container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after some digging in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CEKlopfenstein/Halite-1/blob/master/admin/md/INSTALL.md&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;admin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; folder in the repository I found another set of install instructions. And while this didn’t solve all of my problems it did give me enough to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CEKlopfenstein/Halite-1/blob/1df28ef85666b220b2878d16bedad5befc8f04b3/Dockerfile&quot;&gt;get a working Dockerfile&lt;/a&gt;. Though it’s not without it’s possible issues. But for now, it will work for what I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-issues-and-considerations&quot;&gt;Other Issues and Considerations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I had a working way of running the web server then came a couple of other things I need to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of which is in what format I wish to publish a static version of the site. For this project’s timeline, I don’t have the time to fully rewrite the site to be new. And that was never the intention. But what I don’t want is for my version of the site to be mistaken as the original. Or for an attempt to take credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue is the number of “dead links” like the links to the forum. And while I have access to the “homepage’s” code I don’t have access to the forum’s code or data. And given it likely had quite a bit of user data I don’t think I’d want to handle that. There are quite a few dead links and even a few dead paths. Such as downloads to resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with those issues in mind. My plan is as follows. I’m going to modify the Home page and the footer to label the site as a copy of the original. Likely with a link to an Internet Archive version of the site. As well as a link to the original repository. I will also be going through and removing links that lead to dead paths. And for links that lead to the forum I plan on replacing them with equivalent links to Internet Archive versions of it. They might not load as fast as the original forum. But they should at least provide connections to pages that are lost otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deployment&quot;&gt;Deployment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for deployment, I plan to use Github Pages as I have before. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/66610/how-can-i-create-a-site-in-php-and-have-it-generate-a-static-version&quot;&gt;And using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I created a static copy of the site. Allowing it to be easily hosted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-plans&quot;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with this monthly project done. I will likely move on to the next one. However, I do have plans for this. Eventually, I want to better containerize the whole thing. As well as produce some documentation for it. Unfortunately, my current goal of a project a month does not give me the time necessary to do everything. But then again. If I didn’t have the time constraint I’d probably never get things done. So it’s a double-edged sword I suppose. Either way see you all next time. The results of this page are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://ceklopfenstein.github.io/Halite-1/&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><category term="halite-1" /><summary type="html">I first got seriously into programming sometime around my freshman year of High School. This is for a few reasons. But one of the reasons I remember doing so was because of a Minecraft Mod called Computercraft. The mod itself added computers as well as robots, called turtles, that players could program in Lua. And I did this quite a bit and it allowed me to get over some self-doubts. As a result of not wanting to test my programs in the limited environment of the game. I later installed a Lua Interpreter. Which allowed for the creation of quite a few other projects I did. And while most are effectively lost at this point. It was a start to my journey.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setup And Installation Of Venus 1500 Notes</title><link href="/weekly-posts/2024/05/01/Setup-And-Installation-of-Venus-1500.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setup And Installation Of Venus 1500 Notes" /><published>2024-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/2024/05/01/Setup-And-Installation-of-Venus-1500</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/2024/05/01/Setup-And-Installation-of-Venus-1500.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For those who missed the last post. The writing and publishing of the previous post was delayed. So this post intended for April 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; was also delayed. I plan on being back on schedule for the May 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; post. See ya then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here we are again. Another month another post. Except this time it isn’t a project as much as it will be a repository of some information that I would like to share. So this isn’t going to be a single-flowing article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago, I was asked if I could look at an electric sign and see if I could get it working. This was after they had already called the help desk and gotten nowhere. However, they were able to determine their USB to RS-232 adapter was working. So I was asked if I could assist and do some digging. And those efforts bore fruit this time. So with that in mind, this post exists as a cleaner form of the notes I took while doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;links-to-resources-used&quot;&gt;Links To Resources Used&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daktronics.com/en-us/support/venus-1500-learning-center/download&quot;&gt;Venus 1500 V4 Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=57473&quot;&gt;Microsoft SQL Server 2014 Service Pack 3 Express Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daktronics.com/en-us/support/kb/DD3302758&quot;&gt;Manual Installation of Microsoft SQL 2014 for Venus 1500 Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daktronics.com/web-documents/Manuals/ED-13744.pdf&quot;&gt;Galaxy Outdoor Series AF-3190 Manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daktronics.com/web-documents/manuals/ed-13932.pdf&quot;&gt;Venus 1500 Radio Manual - Gen 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#determine-sign-make-and-model&quot;&gt;Determine Sign Model And Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#installation-of-sql-express&quot;&gt;SQL Express 2014 Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#installation-of-venus-1500&quot;&gt;Venus 1500 Installation Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#connecting-with-the-sign&quot;&gt;Connecting Venus 1500 to the Sign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;determine-sign-make-and-model&quot;&gt;Determine Sign Make and Model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information below was derived from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daktronics.com/web-documents/Manuals/ED-13744.pdf&quot;&gt;Galaxy Outdoor Series AF-3190 Manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn off the sign.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait at least 30 seconds (allow the sign to fully turn off) and turn it back on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Record the next 16 lines of text that the sign provides you. They provide the following information in order. Example values are in parentheses.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Product Name (Galaxy®)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Display Size (Row x Column)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Shading (64 Mono)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bootloader Version (OS X.XX)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Firmware Number (ED13305)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Firmware Revision (Rev X.XX)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hardware Address (HW:XX)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Software Address (SW:XX)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;IP Address: ((default) 172.16.192.25)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Subnet Msk: ((default) Msk: 255.255.0.0)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;COM 1 Configuration (C1:V15) ((Modem C1:V15) If a Modem is present)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;COM 2 Configuration (C2:RTD)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Socket 3001: (IP 3001: V15)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Socket 3002: (IP 3002: RTD)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Line Frequency (CLK: AUTO 60 Hz)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Display Name Description (Galaxy Row x Column)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the sign has listed the last item it will proceed with displaying the last stored settings. If it is the first time the sign has booted a pixel in the lower right-hand corner will flash to indicate that it is on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would recommend writing down this information somewhere you can easily find it later. As it is useful when configuring the sign once you have Venus 1500 installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-of-sql-express&quot;&gt;Installation of SQL Express&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During testing, it was found that for the most reliable success in the installation of Venus 1500, it is best to manually install SQL Express first. Before attempting to install Venus 1500. Even though the installer for Venus 1500 is supposed to install the SQL Server itself. It appears to fail relatively frequently. (Or at least in my experience of around 20 attempts total.) Official instructions are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daktronics.com/en-us/support/kb/DD3302758&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or using the &lt;a href=&quot;#links-to-resources-used&quot;&gt;Links to Resources Used&lt;/a&gt; section. Follow them as they are written. I did not find any needed changes. Download link for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=57473&quot;&gt;SQL Express 2014&lt;/a&gt; is available at the link or in the &lt;a href=&quot;#links-to-resources-used&quot;&gt;Links to Resources Used&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation-of-venus-1500&quot;&gt;Installation of Venus 1500&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For installing Venus 1500 V4 following the instructions posted on their site is advised and can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daktronics.com/en-us/support/venus-1500-learning-center/download&quot;&gt;found here&lt;/a&gt; along with the download for the software. However, I would advise installing &lt;a href=&quot;#installation-of-sql-express&quot;&gt;the SQL server&lt;/a&gt; manually due to some issues with the installer failing to do it on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, I have one other piece of advice while going through the install wizard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/venus-1500/RestartDialog.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, in a dialog I was unable to capture, the install process may ask you to attempt to either restart a service or reboot the PC later. If this option is presented to you I recommend performing a reboot. This is for a couple of reasons. For example. If it fails to restart the service, at least from my testing, it reverts your install process. Whereas if you select the option to restart later it can complete its installation. I would also suggest you manually restart rather than clicking &lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt; in the above dialog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connecting-with-the-sign&quot;&gt;Connecting with the Sign&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the wizard will work just fine for most applications. The one thing I’d like to note is you will need to ensure that the USB to RS232 adapter is assigned to COM1 or COM2. This was the main issue I ran into when assisting with the sign. We could get the program to boot. Everything else worked. But we could not communicate with the sign through RS232. With the adapter not even indicating activity using it’s TX and RX lights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What appears to be the issue is for some reason Windows 10 does not like to properly use Serial devices with the correct protocal for RS232 on anything other than COM1 or COM2. I actually remembered reading this somewhere. But unfortunately I can’t seem the original source. And attempting to Google it leads to people having problems with the Adapter itself that may or may not be related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-change-portcheck-the-port&quot;&gt;How to Change Port/Check the Port&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Open the Windows Device Manager and find the Ports list.
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;You can get to Windows device Manager by right clicking the Start Menu.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;div style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/venus-1500/step1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Click &quot;Show hidden devices&quot;
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This may not be needed if you already see your device listed.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;div style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/venus-1500/step2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/venus-1500/step3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Enter the properties of your device.
        &lt;div style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/venus-1500/step4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto;display:block;width:100%;max-width:400px&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Go the &quot;Port Settings&quot; Tab.
        &lt;div style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/venus-1500/step5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Click &quot;Advanced&quot;
        &lt;div style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/venus-1500/step6.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Click the &quot;COM Port Number:&quot; dropdown to change the port.
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If your serial adapter is already on COM1 or COM2 then you can stop here.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If your serial adapter is not on COM1 or COM2 then change it and click OK.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If COM1 or COM2 have a &quot;(in use)&quot; beside them you will need to determine which device is on it and change it first. Using the steps above.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;div style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/venus-1500/step7.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><summary type="html">For those who missed the last post. The writing and publishing of the previous post was delayed. So this post intended for April 15th was also delayed. I plan on being back on schedule for the May 15th post. See ya then.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gotify Repeater Plugin</title><link href="/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2024/04/13/GotifyRepeaterPlugin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gotify Repeater Plugin" /><published>2024-04-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-04-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2024/04/13/GotifyRepeaterPlugin</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/golang/gotify-plugins/2024/04/13/GotifyRepeaterPlugin.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I would like to note. This was originally planned for completion and release on the 15th of March. That time has come and gone. And as a result, I would like to say that the April post may also be delayed. The normal schedule will hopefully be restored by May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since sometime in November I’ve been running a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gotify.net/&quot;&gt;Gotify Server&lt;/a&gt; on my Proxmox Instance. With the initial intention being to use it to receive notifications from Proxmox. And for that, Gotify functions fine. The issue though is that it’s missing on feature I wanted. And that being the ability for the server to act as a repeater/proxy for other services that can send out notifications. But since Gotify has plugin support I figured I could write up that functionality myself. So I got started on figuring out how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-setup&quot;&gt;Project Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now luckily enough finding the documentation for it was pretty easy. They have a GitHub Repository called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gotify/plugin-template&quot;&gt;plugin-template&lt;/a&gt; (what a creative name) that provides the needed files for a simple “hello world” plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it didn’t work quite write on the Ubuntu VM have been SSHing into to tinker with Go. The first of being that I have not configured Docker to be able to be run without using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;. But that was a simple fix by just adding it to the Makefile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other issue. Which seemed strange. Was the inability to find a program called &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gomod-cap&lt;/code&gt;. With the commands originally being &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gomod-cap -from ${BUILDDIR}/gotify-server.mod -to go.mod&lt;/code&gt;. Looking through the Makefile I found that one of the Makefile’s targets appears to “install” it using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GO111MODULE=off go get -u github.com/gotify/plugin-api/cmd/gomod-cap&lt;/code&gt;. Unfortunately, while that was functioning. It didn’t install it in such a way that it would be runnable as a stand-alone command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead I replaced &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gomod-cap&lt;/code&gt; within that command to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;go run github.com/gotify/plugin-api/cmd/gomod-cap&lt;/code&gt; which works like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npx&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt; world. Where it downloads the script as a temp file and executes it. Now that’s likely not the best solution but that’s what I did to get started. Eventually, I’ll get around to understanding why it didn’t work. But on with the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there I modified it to Makefile to give me a target that would build the amd64 version of the plugin and then place it in the correct location where a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docker-compose&lt;/code&gt; file would pick it up for a test gotify server. Loading the newest version of the plugin into a gotify server every time I ran the target. Which finally gave me an environment to at least test whether this idea would even work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-prototype&quot;&gt;Initial Prototype&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first up I created a VERY simple demo/prototype just to make sure what I was going to do was even achievable. Initially, I had thought that there would be the ability to hook into an event listener. But that doesn’t exist directly within the Plugin interface. So what I ended up doing, and what someone else did in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/elgonlabs/gotify-emailer/&quot;&gt;different plugin that does this to send emails&lt;/a&gt; after the fact, was to use the REST API to get a WebSocket connection that does exactly what I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That requires two things then. An HTTP or HTTPS path to the gotify server, cause we can’t guarantee it will be within docker or on a different port than standard. And a client token that can be used for authentication. So this being a proof of concept I simply hard-coded those values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there I ended up fiddling around and failing quite frequently to get a Websocket to connect when the server started up and the plugin enabled itself. Until I realized that I was attempting to connect to nothing because Gotify initializes the plugins before it starts accepting traffic. 🤦&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after that was fixed. I then created a loop that would read the messages received from the socket and send out a Discord Webhook every time it received something. And what would you know? It worked. After some trial and error and learning more about how Go handles JSON. But hey can’t make an omelet without breaking a few legs. But it worked as a proof of concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-0&quot;&gt;Version 0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I wanted to make something with what I considered the bare minimum of functional, at least for a kind of Version 0. So I came up with a list of requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must Properly Handle enabling and disabling of the plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No Hard Coded Values. (URL for Gotify, Client Token, Discord Webhook)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configurable from within Gotity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple Formatted Discord Message&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information about the plugin displayed within Gotify “Displayer” per the recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of which are relatively simple. Most of it more or less is refactoring the already existing demo and properly handling the errors that it might run into. But the result looked like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/image-box.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image0&quot; class=&quot;image-box-modal&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gotify-plugin/Plugin_Screen_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/modal.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image0modal&quot; class=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;modal-content&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;span id=&quot;image0modal-close&quot; class=&quot;close&quot;&gt;&amp;times;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gotify-plugin/Plugin_Screen_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;script&gt;
        // Open Modal Event Listener
        document.getElementById(&quot;image0&quot;).onclick = function () {
            document.getElementById(&quot;image0modal&quot;).style.display = &quot;block&quot;;
            // One of Two Modal Close Event Listeners (Click outside of Modal)
            window.onclick = function (event) {
                if (event.target == document.getElementById(&quot;image0modal&quot;)) {
                    document.getElementById(&quot;image0modal&quot;).style.display = &quot;none&quot;;
                }
            }
        }

        // One of Two Modal Close Event Listeners (Click X to close)
        document.getElementById(&quot;image0modal-close&quot;).onclick = function () {
            document.getElementById(&quot;image0modal&quot;).style.display = &quot;none&quot;;
        }


    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And overall it functions exactly as I was hoping it would though it’s not perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discovered-flawsnext-version&quot;&gt;Discovered Flaws/Next Version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I deployed version 0 of my plugin to my Gotify Server I decided to run some tests. Unfortunately, these tests presented some issues I didn’t have when running it for short periods when developing. Such as the fact that the plugin currently can not recover itself in the event the Websocket is closed for whatever reason. Requiring the user to disable and enable the plugin to fix it. Another issue and one I didn’t think I’d have to deal with is the fact that a Gotify event message can contain extra information. Which I discovered Proxmox makes use of. So that now needs to be handled and can’t be ignored. So onward with the improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;version-1---working-so-much-better&quot;&gt;Version 1 - Working So Much Better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now first off with version 1 came the corrections to quite a few bugs from testing. Which included the inability of the plugin to recover from connection issues. And while I’m not an expert at this point I think I’ve more or less solved it in this case. The problem with Proxmox was also solved relatively quickly by simply not parsing the entire message structure. Only parsing the parts I’m currently using which at this point seems to be the smarter move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But fixing bugs wasn’t the only thing I wanted in version one. I also wanted to improve the interface for configuring the plugin. And while the Configurator is probably great for some projects. I wanted an interface that could guide the user. At least to some degree. So I began to implement it using the Webhooker Gotify provides and &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmx.org/&quot;&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I must say. I can see the usefulness of &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmx.org/&quot;&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt;. It allowed me to not have to mess with front-end Javascript to be able to lazy load data or even submit data back to the server. You just have the HTTP server, or in this case, the Gotify server, to respond with properly formatted HTML, which provided me with a very simple way to easily build the kind of interface I needed. At least once I had the time and learned some of its quirks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image1&quot; class=&quot;image-box-modal&quot;&gt;
        
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gotify-plugin/Plugin_Interface.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;image1modal&quot; class=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;modal-content&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;span id=&quot;image1modal-close&quot; class=&quot;close&quot;&gt;&amp;times;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gotify-plugin/Plugin_Interface.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;script&gt;
        // Open Modal Event Listener
        document.getElementById(&quot;image1&quot;).onclick = function () {
            document.getElementById(&quot;image1modal&quot;).style.display = &quot;block&quot;;
            // One of Two Modal Close Event Listeners (Click outside of Modal)
            window.onclick = function (event) {
                if (event.target == document.getElementById(&quot;image1modal&quot;)) {
                    document.getElementById(&quot;image1modal&quot;).style.display = &quot;none&quot;;
                }
            }
        }

        // One of Two Modal Close Event Listeners (Click X to close)
        document.getElementById(&quot;image1modal-close&quot;).onclick = function () {
            document.getElementById(&quot;image1modal&quot;).style.display = &quot;none&quot;;
        }


    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In creating the interface I also ended up adding some new features that can be seen in the image above. Such as the ability to more easily set the token that the plugin will use to listen for messages. As well as the ability to manage “transmitters” which is what I’m going to be calling the different destinations that the plugin can relay messages to. With there currently only being two. The “Log Transmitter” and one for Discord Webhooks. Eventually, I plan on expanding the selection but for now, this works for demonstration purposes and my current use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this is being built using &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmx.org/&quot;&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt; for the interaction with the server itself (all the APIs I created require a valid token) and Bootstrap 5 for some CSS. Which I’m pretty pleased about. And now with that done and working I can comfortably begin the next month’s project. Now to figure out what it is. Well, I have some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone else may find this plugin useful it is currently available in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CEKlopfenstein/gotify-repeater&quot;&gt;public Github Repo here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><category term="golang" /><category term="gotify-plugins" /><summary type="html">I would like to note. This was originally planned for completion and release on the 15th of March. That time has come and gone. And as a result, I would like to say that the April post may also be delayed. The normal schedule will hopefully be restored by May.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tinkering with Go and Google Sheets API (Budget Data Pulldown)</title><link href="/weekly-posts/golang/budget-app/2024/02/15/Learning-Go.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tinkering with Go and Google Sheets API (Budget Data Pulldown)" /><published>2024-02-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-02-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/golang/budget-app/2024/02/15/Learning-Go</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/golang/budget-app/2024/02/15/Learning-Go.html">&lt;p&gt;Well. It’s that time of month again. And this time I’ve been tinkering around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.dev/&quot;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; by building a small program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program in question does a couple things. The intention being to pull data from a Google Sheet that I update with financial information and place that data into an SQLite database file. So first things first. Getting Google Sheets to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-sheets-authentication&quot;&gt;Google Sheets Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google Sheets API, and other Google APIs those that interact with user data, require the use of OAuth2. Now I could have used an already developed Library for it. In fact Google has an official one for Go. Except I prefer to write my own. Especially for personal projects. And given the Sheet’s REST API isn’t to complicated I decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it turns out that I’m by far the first one to want to do this. In fact someone wrote a rather &lt;a href=&quot;https://rsseau.fr/2020-10-28-google-oauth&quot;&gt;nice article&lt;/a&gt; on how to Authenticate simply using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cURL&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-golang highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// client id and secret obtained from Google API Console:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// https://console.developers.google.com/apis/credentials&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clientId&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Getenv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;ID&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clientSecret&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Getenv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;SECERET&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// Redirect URL. Do not need any webserver for now because this will only&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// allow us to copy the redirection URL provided by Google&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;redirect&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;http://localhost:8080&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// Scope, that means actions you'll be able to make with obtained token&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// (this is a space separated list)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scope&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;https://www.googleapis.com/auth/webmasters.readonly&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;https://accounts.google.com/o/oauth2/auth?client_id=&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clientId&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;amp;redirect_uri=&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;redirect&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;amp;scope=&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scope&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;amp;response_type=code&amp;amp;access_type=offline&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;link&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// Get the value of CODE. Retrievable from resulting URL that the login link&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// redirects to.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;srv&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Server&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;HandleFunc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ResponseWriter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;codeResp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;code&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;codeResp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;codeResp&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// Delayed shutdown of HTTP server&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;go&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Sleep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;500&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Millisecond&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;srv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Shutdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Fprintln&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;You are now logged in.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// code from URL&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;code&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;code&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;client_id&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clientId&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;client_secret&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clientSecret&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;redirect_uri&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;redirect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;access_type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;offline&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;grant_type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;authorization_code&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;https://accounts.google.com/o/oauth2/token&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;application/x-www-form-urlencoded&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;strings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;NewReader&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Encode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ReadAll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// Struct that can be contain the unmarshaled JSON&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;responseJSON&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;responseBit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/*
{
  &quot;access_token&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
  &quot;expires_in&quot;: 3599,
  &quot;refresh_token&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
  &quot;scope&quot;: &quot;https://www.googleapis.com/auth/webmasters.readonly&quot;,
  &quot;token_type&quot;: &quot;Bearer&quot;
}

*/&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;responseJSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;access token&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;responseJSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Access_token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;refresh token&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;responseJSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Refresh_token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// Example of refreshing TOKEN using refresh Token&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;refresh&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;refresh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;client_id&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clientId&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;refresh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;client_secret&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clientSecret&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;refresh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;refresh_token&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;responseJSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Refresh_token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;refresh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;grant_type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;refresh_token&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;https://accounts.google.com/o/oauth2/token&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;application/x-www-form-urlencoded&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;strings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;NewReader&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;refresh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Encode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ReadAll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;// Another struct that is very similar to responseBit minus the refresh token&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;refreshInfo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/*
{
  &quot;access_token&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
  &quot;expires_in&quot;: 3599,
  &quot;scope&quot;: &quot;https://www.googleapis.com/auth/webmasters.readonly&quot;,
  &quot;token_type&quot;: &quot;Bearer&quot;
}
*/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Status: &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Access Token: &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Access_token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Sleep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Second&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above was effectively what I started out with. Using the instructions provided in the article I converted it to be useful in Go. And to test that whether the access token I used the following. With the token being placed within a HTTP Header.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-golang highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;req&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;NewRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;MethodGet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;https://www.googleapis.com/oauth2/v3/tokeninfo&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;req&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Header&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Authorization&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Bearer &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;access_token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;client&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;client&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;req&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;defer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ReadAll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that the ability to get and use the access token I then needed a way to ensure that the access token maintains. And from doing some research I learned that this is possible with using a Go &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;channel&lt;/code&gt; and a Ticker. Which was actually really simple. Then then led to mean learning how to make methods for Go &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;structs&lt;/code&gt;. Do I then effectively packaged all of the Google authentication into a single package. With the access_token not being accessible outside of the package. Instead when you need to preform a request with the access token I have provided a method that is effectively a mapping of a basic &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; request with the needed header added within it. The method then returning the body of the response or the error in the event something when wrong. The code below effectively being the same as in the code block directly above this paragraph except using the new Methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-golang highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;queryResult&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;auth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GetQuery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;PRINT INFO ERROR:&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;PRINT INFO: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;queryResult&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of this to prevent the need to constantly sign in. The program also saves the refresh token in a secure manner and attempt to use that first before requesting the user to log in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-sheets-api&quot;&gt;Google Sheets API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next came the access of the actual Google Sheet. Which first required me to enable the Google Sheet API for the OAuth 2.0 Client IDs I have provided the program. After that I then needed to add another scope. Which is achieved (as need above in a comment) by appending the correct Scope URL. Which is my case is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://www.googleapis.com/auth/spreadsheets.readonly&lt;/code&gt; which provides read only access to the Signed in User’s Google Sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there the REST API is quite &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/sheets/api/reference/rest&quot;&gt;well documented&lt;/a&gt; with all the requests I’m interested in being &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; requests making it even simpler by not requiring formatted payloads. I just needed to create the needed &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;structs&lt;/code&gt; that would allow me to interact with the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sqlite-database&quot;&gt;SQLite Database&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there I had the ability to pull data. I had to determine how to store it in the SQLite database file. Now instead of implementing SQLite 3 myself I did use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mattn/go-sqlite3&quot;&gt;an external library&lt;/a&gt; but given the complexity, and the fact I wanted to do this in a month, it was the best option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now most of the sheet’s within my Google Sheet have 6 Columns. Those being Date, Balance, Debit, Credit, Title, and Notes. With there being 9 different sheets that I wanted to pull down. So what I created two basic tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sql highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;CREATE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;TABLE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;IF&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;EXISTS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;integer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;PRIMARY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;KEY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account_name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;CREATE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;TABLE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;IF&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;EXISTS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trans_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;integer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;PRIMARY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;KEY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;integer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;TEXT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;integer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FOREIGN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;KEY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One two store sheet names (and eventually other data about that particular sheet but hey that’s a future project) and another to store the actual transactions. Where instead of having three columns containing data on the transaction I have one. Being the change in the account. From there (and by making the assumption all accounts start at 0) I can then find the balance. And if I want to create a table similar to my old sheets I can use the following SQL command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sql highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trans_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;&quot;$%.2f&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ROUND&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; 
                            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;SUM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
                          &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trans&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; 
                          &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;WHERE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;account&lt;/span&gt; 
                            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trans_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trans_id&lt;/span&gt;
                         &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;balance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;CASE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;WHEN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;THEN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;&quot;$%.2f&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;ELSE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;END&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;debit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;CASE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;WHEN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;THEN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;&quot;$%.2f&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;ELSE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;END&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;trans&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-loading&quot;&gt;Data Loading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there came the need to load which was done with some simple &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;INSERT&lt;/code&gt; statements and some logic that handled determine if the rows in the sheet where to be negative or positive. Which wasn’t to bad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-golang highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GetValues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sheetName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;A1:F&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;transFound&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GetAccountTransactionCount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;accountID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;transFound&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;toWrite&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[][]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rowIndex&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rowIndex&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rowIndex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;toWrite&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;toWrite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rowIndex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Writing %d rows from %s to %d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;toWrite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sheetName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;accountID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;WriteTransaction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;accountID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;toWrite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;%s up to date with %d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sheetName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;accountID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function this was contained in also allowed me to preform the insertions only when there are more rows in the Sheet than corresponding rows within the DB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why&quot;&gt;But Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the why I did this. There are two reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve been wanting to make a program that allows me to preform “better” analysis on the data within this Google sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m currently using Gotify within my Proxmox Instance. And by default it does not have a way to integrate with Discord Webhooks. And given it’s written in Go and I can expand it using plugins. My next project is to then add that functionality. Which I hope to post about next month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s really it. Eventually I plan on expanding this. Maybe even creating an interface for it so it can present graphs. But until then it has provided me a place to muck around with Go before having to interact with with the Gotify plugin system. And I must say. I might start using Go for more of my prototyping than Javascript or Python. I like how it feels compared to them. Especially with the fact it feels more like C which I always enjoyed writing. It just takes quite a bit of work to get something beyond basic functionality working. With Go providing a rather impressive standard library.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><category term="golang" /><category term="budget-app" /><summary type="html">Well. It’s that time of month again. And this time I’ve been tinkering around with Go by building a small program.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year, Resolutions Old and New, and Project Management Software</title><link href="/weekly-posts/2024/01/15/2024-Has-Begun.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year, Resolutions Old and New, and Project Management Software" /><published>2024-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/weekly-posts/2024/01/15/2024-Has-Begun</id><content type="html" xml:base="/weekly-posts/2024/01/15/2024-Has-Begun.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-years&quot;&gt;New Years!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well. It’s now been 2024 for a couple weeks now. But hey better late than never to make some resolutions. So let’s end this post with a couple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;last-year-resolutions&quot;&gt;Last Year Resolutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all let’s make an assessment of last year’s resolutions. Those being the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make progress and or complete at least 3 of my personal projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make more regular posts here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a job lined up for after Graduation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socialize more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple list that seemed achievable for the most part. Unfortunately though they didn’t all stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;heavy_check_mark-completionprogress-on-projects&quot;&gt;:heavy_check_mark: Completion/Progress on projects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’m going to be honest. I originally went in to this with the plan to finish my project management project first. And then work on a couple other projects. In reality I only “shelved” a project. That being to create a “map” of what Wikipedia article is related to each other. Which is slightly mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;/weekly-posts/d3/2023/04/15/D3-exploration.html&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;. And that was only done because it sounded like an interested project that I could use for a class project where I could effectively scale the amount of data I saved to a database, which was a concern due to the project having a requirement of using “a reasonably sized data set”. And in this point I’ve shelved farther development on it due to the SHEAR number of connections I found doing it in that limited sense. As a result I concluded while it would be interesting in the future. I do not have the time to pursue that now. That and there are a couple academic papers on it I found. So that was fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for completing or shelfing other projects. I, rather effectively, used the fact I hadn’t finished my management project to stall the starting or even finishing of other projects. Which is just a problem I have of starting and then forgetting about projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I can actually still mark this resolution as a success. I just have to stretch my original intention. Which was that I was going to complete projects on my list at that time. If I count other projects I did end up completing a couple more. Like a making a Discord bot and setting up a Proxmox server. So taking that into account, success on that front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;x-more-regular-posts&quot;&gt;:x: More Regular Posts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another of my resolutions though was to make one regular posts. With the original resolution being and I quote. “Once every two weeks? I really need to determine some sort of schedule.” Which become the original plan. Which then changed in May to be once a month on the 15th or 16th of each month. But given that between then and now I’ve only made a grand total of 2 other posts. I think that plan fell through hard. So I’m going to count this one as a complete miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wavy_dash-lining-up-a-job&quot;&gt;:wavy_dash: Lining up a Job&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to honestly count this as an almost. Cause I did get a job within less than a month of graduating. And that did take some effort (and maybe a little bit of luck). But hey I’m happy in my current position. And am still there which is great. Below being a table of what it took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Count&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Applications&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;74&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rejections&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;31&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Stopped Pursing for Personal Reasons&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ghosts&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Interviews (Some Multiple)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Accepted Offer&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wavy_dash-socializing&quot;&gt;:wavy_dash: Socializing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of hard to quantify it but I have been getting out a little more. But I could still improve it. I’m not going to dig any farther into it than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-resolutions&quot;&gt;New Resolutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So effectively I completed 2/4 of my resolutions if we want to consider half successes as 0.5. Now what about 2024. Well we’re going to learn a bit from the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a better method of managing projects and actually use it.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This NEEDS done. Something other than Github Projects cause that doesn’t work as well as I would hope.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make progress or complete 3 projects
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Repeat of last year but hey. It’s something I still want to do. And I could do better.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monthly Posts
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Again a repeat of last year. But I think it’s more obtainable than the every two weeks. I just need to take the time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be more productive.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is rather generic. But most resolutions are. I just have felt my ambition slipping recently for a couple reasons and I need to turn that around.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-management&quot;&gt;Project Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now on to something else. And that’s how I’m going to achieve some of these resolutions. And that’s deciding what I’m going to use for project management. So that began a bit of a search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;desired-qualitiesfeatures&quot;&gt;Desired Qualities/Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first off. My requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off is that it needs to be free and open source. That mostly being because I don’t want to worry about paying for it at the moment. That may change in the future but for now that’s how I’m going to roll. Next is a preference I didn’t think I’d have originally but found I find of need. And that is that it be web based. Mostly being so I don’t have to access my notes and projects from a specific computer. Which leads me into the other requirement being that I want it to be self hosted on my Proxmox instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-found&quot;&gt;What I Found&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in my search I found the following options. Not all of which though that fit my requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Selection&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Solution&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;My Requirements&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Features&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Reason For Not Selecting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openproject.org/&quot;&gt;Open Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:none;margin: 0; padding: 0&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Free&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Web App&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Self Hosted&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Project Portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Project Planning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Task Management&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Time Tracking&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team Collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Roadmaps&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Workflows&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;More features that I need for personal use.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plane.so/&quot;&gt;Plane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:none;margin: 0; padding: 0&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Free&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Web App&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Self Hosted&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Multiple Presentation Methods for Tasks (List, Kanban, Calendar)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Custom Workflows&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;(Planned) Integration into quite a few services.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Togglable Features (Turn on only what you need)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Themes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Requires install script (don't personally want to run a random install script that spins up containers without clear explanation)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Still in heavy development.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.focalboard.com/&quot;&gt;Focalboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:none;margin: 0; padding: 0&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Free&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Web App&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Self Hosted&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Multiple Visualization Methods. (Board, List, Calendar, Gallery)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Collaboration Support&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Many templates.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lost support of it's starting company September 2023&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;No ability to set relations between tasks or &quot;projects&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://appflowy.io/&quot;&gt;AppFlowy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:none;margin: 0; padding: 0&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Free&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Web App&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Self Hosted&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Offline Mode&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Has &quot;AI&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Projects&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tasks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lists&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hierarchical Notes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Currently does not have a web based mode. (It appears one is coming)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Might switch to or tinker with once the &quot;Cloud&quot; version is publicly released. Hopefully it can be self hosted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Selected&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vikunja.io/&quot;&gt;Vikunja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:none;margin: 0; padding: 0&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Free&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Web App&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Self Hosted&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Projects&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Task&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Task Relations&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Repeating Tasks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Multiple presentation modes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;At this point in time is supports the functionality I want. And has a simple docker compose file.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phproject.org/&quot;&gt;PHProject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:none;margin: 0; padding: 0&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Free&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Web App&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false&quot; /&gt; Self Hosted&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Issues&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Backlog&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Taskboard&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Attempting to install using docker failed. With 404 errors when using the same configuration as in the document.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Demo currently returning a 521 HTTP error. (As of 2024-01-13)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m no one to talk about what systems are the best. But when I went into this I wanted something where I could take my notes, create projects, and track tasks within those projects. And at this point in time. Vikunja seems to fit the bill at least when it comes to the task of projects and tasks. Unfortunately it doesn’t explicitly support notes like I want. But for how well it works for me at the moment I’m going to see how well it works. If anything I’m going to use it for a year. That’s the goal. If I can successfully use it then that first resolution is done. Hopefully assisting me with the others. We’ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="weekly-posts" /><summary type="html">New Years! Well. It’s now been 2024 for a couple weeks now. But hey better late than never to make some resolutions. So let’s end this post with a couple. Last Year Resolutions First of all let’s make an assessment of last year’s resolutions. Those being the following. Make progress and or complete at least 3 of my personal projects. Make more regular posts here. Get a job lined up for after Graduation. Socialize more!</summary></entry></feed>